Ameeta Dalvi

ameetadalvi@gmail.com (720) 496 9566 l Bellevue, WA ameetadalvi.com

An Architect turned User Experience Designer, I believe in creating effective, reliable and delightful solutions. I have 5 years of Design experience focusing on user-centric approach, problem-solving and thoughtful construction. I seek opportunities that challenge me to think big and convert those ideas into reality.

Experience

User Experience Designer - Contract

Orb Sense, Seattle | August - September 2016

- Developed an iOS application for a smart kitchen product that assists users in their cooking process and allows them to confidently step away from an active kitchen.
- Acted as a Project Lead of team of three and managed the schedule for the project to ensure our team meets the set goals and delivers on time.
- Conducted comprehensive user research and usability testing to understand if the product truly fulfills a real need and adds value to users' cooking process.
- Designed sketches, wireframes and developed multiple iterations of rapid prototypes for user testing and design development.

Volunteer Consultant

Mueller Consulting, Atlanta | 2014-2015

 Supported activities like resource on-boarding, management and design of website, and templates for communication, engagement with clients and content development.

Design Architect with focus on Sustainability

Edifice Architects, Mumbai | 2013

- Built designs that were functional, visually appealing and sustainable in nature. Deeply involved in gathering data and analyzing it to inform design solutions.
- Developed initial design concepts(sketches) into detailed layouts(wireframes) based on feedback from clients, engineers and consultants
- Built 3D models (prototypes) to study solar radiation, optimize daylight and avoid glare thus contributing towards lower energy consumption of buildings.
- Projects ranged from residential to commercial and urban planning.

Design Architect with focus on Sustainability

Zyscovich Architects, Miami | 2010 - 2012

- Created design prototypes at early stages to evaluate different design options and improve the overall energy performance of buildings.
- Developed a viable LEED (Certification Program for Green Buildings) strategy and goal for each project, informed clients about the energy needs and possibilities of energy savings for their projects and worked towards achieving the highest LEED rating.
- Collaborated with Engineers and Consultants on sustainable design strategies and details.
- Worked on ideas to educate users about principles of sustainability and how to incorporate it in everyday life.

Design Architect

Atul Desai and Associates, Mumbai | 2008 - 2009

• Designed initial concepts and worked on detailed construction drawings.

Design Architect

Bobby Mukherjee and Associates, Mumbai | 2007 - 2008

• Developed design concepts and layouts for houses, clubs and urban planning master plans.

Skills

User-Research
Heuristic Evaluation
Interaction Design
Wireframes
Prototypes
Usability Testing
Problem-solving
Teamwork
Communication

Tools

Prototype tools

Axure RP Sketch Invision POP mybalsamiq Omnigraffle

Design tools

Adobe Illustrator Adobe Photoshop Adobe Lightroom AutoCadd Sketch-Up Ecotect & Radiance Microsoft Office

Coding tools

HTML CSS Javascript

Education

General Assembly, 2016

User Experience Design Immersive

Georgia Institute of Tech. 2010

Master of Science, Architecture

University of Mumbai, 2007

Bachelors of Architecture

Competitions

Hackathon, GA

Team won 2nd place and special mention for UX process